Abrar Ahmed

(+49) 1764-2030519, abraracs@gmail.com

→ https://github.com/abrarum

Berlin, Germany

An experienced individual in the field for **over 7 years**. Co-founded **3 micro-startups**. Artificial intelligence and machine learning research enthusiast focused on **computer vision** esp. **Object detection** problems. My primary focus is on **Deep neural networks**, currently working on a novel solution using **Convolutional neural networks** to solve the Bezier line detection problem for the detection of wood rings and power lines using **Python** and **Tensorflow**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant & Master Thesis

(Computer vision & Machine learning) — Fraunhofer IGD

Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

- Proposed a neural net architecture that directly predicts Bezier lines/curves instead of bounding/anchor boxes for certain specialized applications.
- Examined the neural network interpretability by implementing novel feature visualization techniques by backpropagation, saliency maps, and smooth gradients.
- Skills: Image processing, deep learning, linear algebra, python, tensorflow, opency

Research Assistant (Data Analyst) — Max Planck Institute

Jul 2020 - Mar 2021

- Literature, online and social media search.
- Statistical analysis and support in the preparation of visualizations and reports.
- Skills: Web scraping, data analysis and cleaning, management, and accuracy validation.

Werkstudent (SE Machine learning) — Hamburg Port Consulting Sep 2019 – Nov 2019

- Automated the data pre-processing pipeline reducing the time consumption by 98.3%.
- Derived the optimal container dwell time prediction by implementing time-series analysis and forecasting of the container data with an accuracy of 98%.
- Skills: statistics, time-series analysis, forecasting, tensorflow, specifications

Real-Time Hand Detection using neural networks (Single Shot Detector) — (Opensource)

 Using neural networks solved the hard problem of tracking hands in real-time using a customized first-person POV hand dataset.

Berlin Weather Forecast using Random Forest Algorithm — (Opensource)

• End-to-End Machine learning solution for the prediction of the maximum temperature tomorrow in Berlin using Random forest algorithm.

FINEGAN implementation for Python v3.7 — (Opensource)

Refined the novel FINEGAN implementation supporting Python 3.7 and Pytorch 1.1.0

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Freelancer — Self Employed

Jun 2014 - Mar 2019

- Completed 200+ small and big projects by myself.
- Co-founded 3 micro-startups (Axisport Lab, Graphimator & Stitch-In)
- Skill stack ranges from web dev (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES5/6, VueJS, Angular, React, SQL, NoSQL), app dev (React Native and Android), designer (Adobe Suite), content writing, and SEO.
- Prominent Clients: Cryptozilla.io, Medb diagnostics, Horizon Tech, Productivenous, Al Wahdat Travels, GiveAKidney, Midwestradar, Chotaay Delivery, UPenn, Flexicom, IFI, Individual entrepreneurs, and many more.

EDUCATION

MSc. Computer Science

Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

- Universität Rostock

Convolutional Neural Networks

Sept 2020 - Mar 2021

— Coursera.org